Hello.
Welcome back.
In this lesson, we shall see how to set up our ADC for continuous conversion.
We've already seen how to perform single conversion.
The single conversion is good for every day.
No more low speed project.
But if you want your conversion to happen rapidly or if your project requires rapid conversion, something
that is very fast, such as digital signal processing, then the best or the better solution.
Among the two is the M, the ADC continuous conversion mode.
Later on, we shall see how to incorporate the DMA.
So let's go to Cuba, mix and start off by creating a project.
And then we go to the IDC to write the code.
I'll select my board over here.
You can use it at a nuclear or the disco.
There should be fine.
So clear.
Oh, PS, like I always do.
So we still using the P is.
I'm going to said that as an ADC pin by clicking over here, it's ADC one input's zero.
Okay.
Okay, so let's configure the ADC first.
I'll come to the system clock and just do the normal setup over here first.
I'm going to use the.
This the a wire over here and then RCC like the clocks, the.
Artist.
I just keep this or keep these disabled.
You can, you can.
Whatever choice we make here would reflect in the clock configuration.
Let's just OK, let's bypass high speed external.
When we start using the when we get to the part about.
About the USB devices, we would no longer be able to bypass high speed Extel would start and enabling
it.
But thus far we can afford to bypass it.
Okay.
So once this is done, we can configure the ADC.
Um, I'll come over here.
The analog stub, my computer's running a bit slow.
A click on a log over here.
Did you see one?
And we would need to arm.
We would need to scale down the ATC clock.
So let's go to our clock configuration and see what is the current clock of the ATC.
Click over here.
Clock configuration.
So from the microcontrollers user guide that we downloaded, if you check, you realize that the ADC
is connected to the APB to us over here.
So over here says APB to pay for a clock.
It's 48 megahertz.
Therefore, this is the clock for our ADC currently.
Forty eight make a hit, as we see over here.
If we keep everything here the same.
So, no, no, we know this.
We can go to the configuration of the, uh, the ATC.
We know it's clock is 48 megahertz.
Right.
So if I come over here for ADC configuration, um, if I come up here, we can decide to keep the clock
at 48 megahertz or maybe we think that is too fast and we want to slow down the clock.
So we are given the option to select a divider over here.
We can divide the clock it up by two, four, six or eight.
So if we divide by two, the forty eight megahertz becomes twenty four megahertz.
So the default here says divide by two.
So I'll just keep that over here.
I wouldn't change it.
Next sense, we are working with continuous conversion.
We come over here.
Continuous conversion mode.
It says disabled.
We're gonna change that to enabled.
OK.
And the ADC resolution, if we want to change it, we can change it, we have options.
We can select it a six bit, eight bit, 10 bits or twelve bits.
I'm just going to keep it to the twelve bits and you can rella.
You realize that the higher the resolution, the more Crock's like was required to complete the conversion.
Such the six bits requires nine ADC clock cycles and eight which requires eleven, ten requests.
Thirteen and twelve requires fifteen.
So if we keep this then it's going to take 15 clock cycles for a single conversion.
Also, we have the option to align the data, we can leave this the way it is, right?
Alignment is good and we can come over here.
Also.
If we had multiple channels, then we'd have, um.
We'll have, uh, other Ronke over here.
We'll have multiple ranks, Ronke one, two, three, et cetera.
And we'll be able to select, um, we'll be able to select the arrangement in which the conversion should.
Okay.
What do we want.
Channel ten to be sampled first or Channel One, et cetera.
But of course we have one only we have just one under rank.
Over here.
And this is rank one.
And we can select the sampling time.
Sampling time.
Can either there is three psychos over here or we can go all the way to four eighty cycles so we can
choose for eighty cycles.
So because we already mentioned up here that the sampling time is is, um, uh, also depends on the,
um, the resolution over here.
It says fifteen ADC cycles for twelve pit.
So whatever we select down here for sampling time should be plus that 12 bit.
Right.
So there's four hundred and eighty Cycos plus the twelve pit it takes plus the twelve bit it takes for
twelve plus the fifteen cycos it takes for the twelve pit.
If we were using um um if we were using a ten bit it takes thirteen Cycos.
So Timbits has a constant of thirteen, thirteen Cycos.
If we select a sampling time or for eighty then it becomes four eighty Cycos plus the thirteen Cycos
for our ten bit.
Right.
So that is why we have to select sampling time as well.
Now we can generate our code.
We can, um, we can come over here to project manager or select my two chain before I forget this.
The SDM 32 Kubi d e.
I call this project, um, ADC on this call to a continuous conversion.
Like this.
So we can generate a project.
Once we've given it a name and selected the appropriate to chain quickly by here to generate.
So like we did in the other lesson, we have to start the, um, the ADC like we did before, and then
we create a global variable to get the ADC conversion and store it into it.
So let's do the.
And this mode, we don't need to keep all the ATC related initialization in the while, one infinite
loop.
We just need to call the get value Indiewire one loop.
That is what is supposed to continuously occur to get a value by the ATC start code that can be called
outside the infinite loop because we want to execute that just once.
We need to execute that just once.
Whereas in the other example, in the single conversion mode, we need to always study ATC.
So that's another difference between the two in terms of initialization.
So we can start it over here.
Over here.
Number one, start ADC and we use the same API we use before toll on a score ADC on a score start.
And this takes the ADC handle an address to the ADC handle as its only argument, which is a which is
HP, ADC one course, the ADC Modulus ADC one.
Right.
And um, we will create a global variable here, which I'll call you into that to underscore t.
I'll make it volatile.
And I'll call a sense of value like this.
Right.
So once we've done this, we can get a conversion.
So I'll come over here in our infinite loop.
That is where we get a conversion to get conversion.
I call this.
So all we have to do is store the resort and sense of value.
We use the pole for conversion, just like we did before to get this.
So how?
See how on the scroll ADC it is like this.
And then pole for conversion.
And it takes the um, the ADC handle and the timeout.
So each ADC one is the first argument in the timeout of one.
Emmis is fine.
And this is going to return the ADC value which will store in our global variable, which we named a
sense of value like this.
Okay.
So this all we need to do actually.
So just two steps.
We start the ADC, we get the ADC, we continuously get the ADC in our infinite loop over here like
this.
Okay.
Actually, over here we have to simply use to get value.
We need no pool for ADC conversion.
That is the key difference between the two.
So over here, how ADC on this gets value.
A simple cluster I wrote get conversion here.
And then I came using the wrong function.
So this is it.
We start the ADC and then we get the ADC value as simple as that.
And the reason this works continuously is because with initialize that to be continuous mode.
Right.
So I click over here to build a project.
OK, quick over here.
And it's built in.
We have two errors.
Um, let's see.
I think it's from our new.
OK.
This one here.
There's a mistake here.
And I can know the mistake because whenever you are using the whole library, when you first use the
keyword, all you have to add the name of the module you are dealing with.
So if it was a function that deals with a timer, it would be hard to underscore t I am for timer.
If it's a function that deals with less than a ADC, it has to always be hard on the score ADC.
So of course I made a mistake in typing this.
There should be on the score ADC over here.
And apart from that.
Um, this gets value because we are using continuous conversion mode.
It takes just one argument.
It doesn't take a timeout cause it's gonna be continuously converting.
And, um, we can actually find this function.
We can find this function in our ADC module.
I'll copy the function name as I've written it.
And then we're going to go to our drivers over here, just like we often do to verify the name of the
function.
And then I'll come over here, hold driver, ADC Dot.
See, it should be up here.
It's gonna say too big for the kids.
Not so, um, let's see what are we can view the outline.
OK.
Let's search or do.
Control F and then paste the name of the function here.
And this is the function name.
OK.
Indeed.
And it gets one argument.
It takes one argument and it returns the ADC conversion.
So the process gets the converted value from the data register of regular Cherno each ADC pointer to
ADC Hando type structure.
And the return value is the converted value.
So, okay, we're look good.
Now we can build again.
I'll click over here.
It's built in.
So it's done building those school to debug, I see, click over here.
Select this, okay?
Okay.
So that's my live expressions window.
If you don't have this live expression, it's opened, you can come to window, show you and then you
select live expressions.
It's somewhere here.
This is it.
You click here to open it.
So I'm going to copy ADC volume control, see to copy and then I'll double click in here and then I'll
paste it.
So now this is inside the live expressions.
So I'm going to click here to run the code or click it to run.
And this is my ADC value and I'm going to move my potential meter, which we are using as the SENSEOR.
And as you move, as I move, you can see the ADC value changes.
So if this were to be a light sensor or the ADC value will be changing accordingly based on the amount
of light you received.
If it was a different type of sensor such as temperature or pressure, you would work the same way.
Okay.
So that's all there is for this lesson if you have any questions at all.
Just let me know.
I'll see you later.
Have a nice day.